jaguarusa.com 2019-02-09

# Jaguar - Privacy Policy

We respect and are committed to protecting your privacy. That is why we have adopted this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy lets you know how and for what purposes we are collecting, processing and using your Personal Information (as defined herein). We pledge that we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your Personal Information will only be used in ways that are in compliance with this Privacy Policy. 

**This Privacy Policy is in effect for any web pages, mobile applications, third party social media sites, email lists, on-site electronic data collection, generic information and personal information collected and/or owned by Jaguar Land Rover North America, LLC (“JLR USA”, “our” or “we”), including but not limited to the Jaguar USA and the Land Rover USA websites, no matter the method of collection (e.g., mail, facsimile, sign-up/sign-in page, survey), including collection through this website and any online features, services and/or programs offered by JLR USA (collectively, the “Web Properties”). SureSource LLC d/b/a BrandShop operates our Jaguar USA shopping website located at[http://shop.jaguarusa.com](http://shop.jaguarusa.com/) and Land Rover USA shopping website located at [http://shop.landroverusa.com](http://shop.landroverusa.com/) on our behalf. Your use of the Web Properties is also governed by Terms and Conditions located at https://www.jaguarusa.com/terms-conditions.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, this Privacy Policy is not applicable to any other web pages, mobile applications, social media sites, email lists, generic information and Personal Information collected and/or owned by any entity other than JLR USA, including, but not limited to, Tata Motors, Jaguar Land Rover, Jaguar Cars Limited, Land Rover, and any automobile dealership or service center. Users of the foregoing resources should refer to the Privacy Policy in effect for the applicable owner. For clarity, this Privacy Policy does not apply to your use of the InControl services, which is governed by the InControl Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions found at the websites identified below: 

US Land Rover InControl   
[https://www.landroverusa.com/ownership/incontrol/terms-and-conditions.html](http://www.landroverusa.com/ownership/incontrol/terms-and-conditions.html)   
[https://www.landroverusa.com/ownership/incontrol/privacy-policy.html](http://www.landroverusa.com/ownership/incontrol/privacy-policy.html)

US Jaguar InControl   
[https://incontrol.jaguar.com/jaguar-portal-owner-web/about/privacy-policy#us](http://incontrol.jaguar.com/jaguar-portal-owner-web/about/privacy-policy/AUS)   
[https://incontrol.jaguar.com/jaguar-portal-owner-web/about/terms-and-conditions#us](http://incontrol.jaguar.com/jaguar-portal-owner-web/about/terms-and-conditions/AUS)

This Privacy Policy also does not apply to information collected by JLR USA through a means other than the Web Properties or through the InControl services. If the same information is collected through the Web Properties and through a means other than the Web Properties, then the terms of this Privacy Policy shall apply.

**

We will make an effort to update this web page with any changes to this Privacy Policy and you are encouraged to review this Privacy Policy frequently (the date of the most recent revision to this Privacy Policy appears at the end of this Privacy Policy). 

**_Your California Privacy Rights_**

Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, California residents who provide personal information in connection with obtaining products or services for personal, family or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us once a calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2013 will receive information regarding 2012 sharing activities). 

To obtain this information on behalf of JLR USA, please send an email message to [privacy@jaguarlandrover.com](mailto:privacy@jaguarlandrover.com) with “Request for California Privacy Information” in the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you at your email address in response. 

Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the “Shine the Light” requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response. 

Additionally, because we may collect your Personal Information from time to time, California’s Online Privacy Protection Act requires us to disclose how we respond to “do not track” requests and other similar mechanisms. Currently, our policy is that we do not recognize “do not track” requests from Internet browsers and similar devices. 

**_How Information Is Collected_**

The types of Personal Information we collect may include, among other things (collectively, “Personal Information”): (1) contact information (e.g., name, address, home and mobile telephone numbers, email address); (2) biographical information such as household data, preferences, and demographic information (e.g., date of birth, gender, marital status); (3) Internet protocol (or IP) address, MAC address or device ID/UDID; (4) mother’s maiden name (parent’s name prior to marriage); (5) drivers’ license numbers; (6) asset and income information; (7) bank account and credit/debit card numbers; (8) racial or ethnic origin; (9) purchase information regarding our products and services; (10) vehicle identification numbers (VIN’s); and (11) your physical location, time spent and activity while visiting a participating retailer. 

The means by which JLR USA collects such personal information may include when you: (1) purchase, order, or request information about our products and services through the Web Properties; (2) access a JLR USA social media platform; (3) sign up for email notifications, electronic newsletters, mobile messages (including SMS), or social media notifications from, or on behalf of, JLR USA; (4) enter or participate in a JLR USA contest, event, promotion or sweepstakes, or respond to one of our surveys; (5) provide JLR USA with comments, suggestions or other input through the Web Properties; (6) create a user account for use in connection with the Web Properties (your “User Account”); and (7) while you are physically present at a retailer, by reading the “pings” created by the Wi-Fi and/or mobile radios contained in your mobile device. JLR USA also collects such personal information in our marketing efforts on third party websites. 

We may also receive information about you from third party sources, using Personal Information collected through the Web Properties as the method of identifying you. Our use of that third party-sourced information will be subject to this Privacy Policy. 

JLR USA or a partner may sponsor promotions, sweepstakes or contests through the Web Properties. Your participation is entirely voluntary. You may be asked to provide personally identifiable information including, but not limited to, your name, email address or home address or to answer questions in order to participate. JLR USA may also transfer Personal Information to certain advertising or marketing partners from whom you have requested to receive information. 

**_Additional Ways that Information is Collected Through the Web Properties_**

**Browser Log Files:** Our servers automatically log each visitor to the Web Properties and collect and record certain information about each visitor. This information includes or may include your “Internet Protocol”, or IP, address, browser language, browser type, operating system, domain names, browsing history (including time spent at a domain, time and date of your visit), referring/exit web pages and URLs, and number of clicks. The domain name and IP address reveal nothing personal about the visitor other than the IP address from which the visitor has accessed the Web Properties. 

**Cookies:** From time to time, JLR USA and/or our advertisers or other third parties may send a “cookie” to your computer. A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to your Internet browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive and that can be re-sent to the serving website on subsequent visits. A cookie, by itself, cannot read other data from your hard disk or read other cookie files already on your computer. A cookie, by itself, does not damage your system. We, our advertisers and other third parties may use cookies to identify and keep track of, among other things, those areas of the Web Properties and third party websites that you have visited in the past in order to enhance your next visit to the Web Properties. You can choose whether or not to accept cookies by changing the settings of your Internet browser, but some functionality of the Web Properties may be impaired or not function as intended if you choose not to accept cookies. See the Third Party Opt Out section below. 

**Web Beacons:** Some of our web pages and electronic communications may contain images, which may or may not be visible to you, known as Web Beacons (sometimes referred to as “clear gifs”). Web Beacons collect only limited information that includes a cookie number; time and date of a page view; and a description of the page on which the Web Beacon resides. We may also carry Web Beacons placed by third party advertisers. These Web Beacons do not carry any Personal Information and are only used to track usage of the Web Properties and activities associated with the Web Properties. See the Third Party Opt Out section below. 

**Unique Identifier:** We may assign you a unique internal identifier to help keep track of your future visits. We use this information to gather aggregate demographic information about our visitors, and we use it to personalize the information you see on the Web Properties and some of the electronic communications you receive from us. We keep this information for our internal use, and this information is not shared with others. 

**Third Party Opt Out:** We may allow third-party companies to serve advertisements and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit the Web Properties. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (including, but not limited to, click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to the Web Properties in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party Web Beacon to collect this information, as further described above. Through these technologies, the third party may have access to and use non-personalized information about your online usage activity. 

You can opt-out of certain online behavioral services through any one of the ways described below (you do not need to go to each opt-out site, one is sufficient). After you opt-out, you will continue to receive advertisements, but those advertisements will no longer be as relevant to you. 

  * You can opt-out via the Network Advertising Initiative industry opt-out at [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)
  * You can opt-out via the Consumer Choice Page at [www.aboutads.info.](http://www.aboutads.info/)
  * For those in the U.K., you can opt-out via the IAB UK's industry opt-out at [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).
  * You can configure your web browser (Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer, Safari, etc.) to delete and/or control the use of cookies. More information can be found in the Help system of your browser. It is at your discretion whether you use the opt-out described above or manage cookies via the browser.
  * To opt out of cookies used for Conversant online tracking please click here.

Note: If you opt-out as described above, you should not delete your cookies. If you delete your cookies, you will need to opt-out again. 

**Use of Personal Information**

The Personal Information that we collect is used for four main purposes: 

  1\. to enable the features of the Web Properties, including, but not limited to: (a) operating any competitions or promotions in which you may participate; (b) setting up and managing your online account, including but not limited to our processing your requests for information, and/or providing support services to you; (c) providing services to you, such as providing you information about our vehicles; 

  2\. to improve the Web Properties by determining which of our products, features and services are most popular. We may analyze your information and usage information to enable us and our affiliates to provide services to you and develop new features, functionality and services; 

  3\. to personalize your experience on the Web Properties; and 

  4\. to communicate with you and to inform you about our and third parties’ products and services. When requested by you, we (and/or any of our third party service providers) may send you and keep you updated with information about existing and new services, products and special offers, by email, telephone (including, but not limited to, SMS), mail or by means of any other contact details you provide to us or our affiliates, or to such third party service providers. 

**_When Information Is Disclosed By JLR USA_**

In addition to the other times or occasions on which we might disclose Personal Information about you, we might also disclose Personal Information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to: (1) comply with legal processes and applicable laws; (2) enforce this Privacy Policy; (3) respond to claims that any materials, documents, images, graphics, logos, designs, audio, video and any other information provided to, from or on the Web Properties by you violates the rights of third parties; or (4) protect our rights, property or safety or the rights, property or personal safety of our visitors and the public. 

We use reasonable precautions to keep the information that is disclosed to us secure. We provide Personal Information and non-personally-identifiable information to our parent, subsidiaries, affiliated companies, and other businesses or persons for the purposes of processing such information on our behalf and promoting the goods and services of our trusted business partners (for example, navigation system map updates), some or all of which may store some or all of your information on servers outside of the United States. We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with our Privacy Policy or in a similar, industry-standard manner, and we use reasonable efforts to limit their use of such information and to use other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. The use of your information by one of our trusted business partners may be subject to that party’s own Privacy Policy. 

We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous user usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with third parties to demonstrate the usage patterns for JLR USA’s advertisements, content, functionality promotions, competitions, games and/or services on the Web Properties and/or on third party websites. 

We also reserve the right to disclose Personal Information and/or non-personally-identifiable information in connection with the enforcement of our Terms and Conditions located at Jaguar and [Land Rover](http://www.landroverusa.com/terms-and-conditions.html), to take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, to protect the security or integrity of the Web Properties, and to protect our rights, property, or personal safety of JLR USA, and that of our users or others. 

We reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information, as well as any other information, in connection with the sale or other disposition of all or part of the JLR USA business and/or assets. We also cannot make any representations regarding the use or transfer of your Personal Information or other information that we may have in the event of our bankruptcy, reorganization, insolvency, receivership or an assignment for the benefit of creditors, and you expressly agree and consent to the use and/or transfer of your Personal Information or other information in connection with a sale or transfer of some or all of our assets in any of the above described proceedings. Furthermore, we cannot and will not be responsible for any breach of security by any third parties or for any actions of any third parties that receive any of the information that is disclosed to us. 

The Web Properties may also link to a wide variety of other websites and may contain advertisements of third parties. We are not and cannot be responsible for the privacy policies of those websites of third parties or for how they treat information (including, but not limited to personally identifiable information) about their users. 

**_User Account, Password, and Security_**

For certain features available through the Web Properties, we may require the use of encryption technologies provided for your protection and/or User Account. We use reasonable precautions to protect the privacy of your username, password and User Account information. You, however, are ultimately responsible for protecting your username, password and User Account information from disclosure to third parties, and you are not permitted to circumvent the use of required encryption technologies. You agree to: (a) immediately notify JLR USA of any unauthorized use of your username, password and/or User Account, and/or any other breach of security; and (b) ensure that you log out from your User Account at the end of each session. While we may provide certain encryption technologies and use other reasonable precautions to protect your confidential information and provide suitable security, we do not and cannot guarantee or warrant that any information transmitted through the internet is secure, or that such transmissions are free from delay, interruption, interception or error. 

**_Employment Opportunity Information Collection_**

For individuals interested in job opportunities with JLR USA, the Web Properties links prospective employees to a partner’s website. The partner’s website, which has its own Privacy Policy, collects Personal Information from prospective employees for human resources recruitment purposes. This information is then shared with JLR USA’s human resources department and others within JLR USA who are involved in the recruitment process. The foregoing also applies to job application inquiries that you may transmit to us other than through the Web Properties. 

**_Information From Children_**

We do not collect Personal Information from any person that we know to be under the age of thirteen (13). Specifically, the Web Properties is not intended or designed to attract children under the age of thirteen (13). You affirm that you are either more than 18 years of age, or an emancipated minor, or possess legal parental or guardian consent, and are fully able and competent to enter into the terms, conditions, obligations, affirmations, representations, and warranties set forth in this Privacy Policy, and to abide by and comply with this Privacy Policy. In any case, you affirm that you are over the age of 13, as **THE WEB PROPERTIES ARE NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN UNDER 13 THAT ARE UNACCOMPANIED BY HIS OR HER PARENT OR LEGAL GUARDIAN.**

Parents should be aware that this Privacy Policy will govern our use of Personal Information, but also that information that is voluntarily given by children – or others – in email exchanges, bulletin boards or the like may be used by otherparties to generate unsolicited communications. JLR USA encourages all parents to instruct their children in the safe and responsible use of their Personal Information while using the Internet. 

**_Privacy Outside the Web Properties_**

The Web Properties may contain various links to other websites, including, but not limited to, links to websites of various third party service providers. JLR USA is not and cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any of those other websites. Other than under agreements with certain reputable organizations and companies, and except for third party service providers (as described in this Privacy Policy), we do not share any of the Personal Information that you provide to us with any of the websites to which the Web Properties links, although we may share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information with those other third parties. Please check with those websites in order to determine their privacy policies and your rights under them. 

**_European Union Users_**

If you are visiting us from the European Union, please note that we may transfer your Personal Information outside the European Union for use for any of the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. By using the Web Properties and providing us with your Personal Information, you consent to both our collection and such transfer of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**_Choices With Your Personal Information_**

Whether you submit any Personal Information to JLR USA is entirely up to you. You are under no obligation to provide Personal Information. However, this information is essential for the provision and quality of some of the services we offer to you, so we cannot provide you with certain services if you choose to withhold requested information. 

You may choose to prevent JLR USA from disclosing or using your Personal Information under certain circumstances (“opt-out”). You may opt-out of any disclosure or use of your Personal Information for purposes that are incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or for which you subsequently gave authorization by notifying us by one of the methods at the end of this Privacy Policy, or by following the procedures set forth in an electronic communication from us, if applicable. Furthermore, even where your Personal Information is to be disclosed and used in accordance with the stated purposes in this Privacy Policy, you may elect to opt-out of such disclosure to and use by a third party that is not acting as an agent of JLR USA. There are some uses from which you cannot opt-out, such as our use of your Personal Information in connection with your ownership status of a vehicle or vehicle recall (and similar) notification procedures. 

You acknowledge and agree that if you opt-out and subsequently consent to use of your Personal Information (e.g., as part of a contest, promotion, request for information, sales or service transaction, or sweepstakes), your original opt-out shall no longer be effective. In the case of the foregoing, we may use your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, subject to your right to opt-out at a later date as provided herein. 

Please note that opting out of the disclosure and use of your Personal Information as a prospective employee may prevent you from being hired as an employee by JLR USA to the extent you are using this Web Properties to apply for an open position. 

If JLR USA collects Personal Information from you, such information will not be disclosed or used by JLR USA for purposes that are incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or for which you subsequently gave authorization unless you affirmatively consent to such disclosure and use. 

You may opt out of online behavioral advertising by following the instructions set forth above under the above section “Additional Ways That Information Is Collected Through the Web Properties,” subsection “Third Party Opt Out.” 

**Access and Correction**

To access your Personal Information in the possession of JLR USA and correct inaccuracies of that information in our records, please contact us in the manner specified at the end of this Privacy Policy. We ask individuals to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed and amended before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests in limited circumstances as permitted by applicable privacy legislation. 

**Your Consent To This Privacy Policy**

By using the Web Properties, you consent to the collection and use of your information (including Personal Information) by us as specified above or as we otherwise see fit, in compliance with this Privacy Policy, unless you inform us otherwise by means of the procedure identified below. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy or some part of it, we will make an effort to post those changes on this web page so that you will always be able to understand what information we collect, how we use that information and under what circumstances we may disclose that information to others. Your use of the Web Properties following your acceptance of any amendment of this Privacy Policy will signify your assent to and acceptance of its revised terms for all previously collected information and information collected from you in the future. We may use comments, information or feedback that you may submit in any manner that we may choose without notice or compensation to you. 

If you have additional questions or comments of any kind, or if you see anything on the Web Properties that you think is inappropriate or incorrect, please let us know by email or by sending your comments or requests to: 

Jaguar Land Rover North America, LLC   
100 Jaguar Land Rover Way   
Mahwah, New Jersey 07495   
Attn: Customer Care – Privacy Issues   
© 2019 Jaguar Land Rover North America, LLC. All Rights Reserved.   
EFFECTIVE AS OF: March 1, 2013   
LAST UPDATED: September 7, 2018
